Preliminary Guide to the Office of Continuing Studies records, 1969-1992
Duke University. University Archives
Office of Continuing Studies records 1969-1992
Duke University. Office of Continuing Studies.
36 linear feet
Duke University. University Archives
Contains the records of the Office of Continuing Studies, established in 1969 as the Office of Continuing Education at Duke University. The Office provides year-round training, short courses, certificate programs, and credit courses for students and non-students wishing to further their education or prepare for standardized tests. In 1992, the Office of Continuing Education merged with the Summer Session office to create the Office of Continuing Education and Summer Session. Types of materials include student records, subject files, correspondence, progress reports, program proposals, newsletters, annual reports, minutes, flyers, pamphlets, clippings, grant applications, directories, and course schedules. Major subjects include Duke University, career guidance, Office of Continuing Education, Center for Career Development and Continuing Education, and Office of Continuing Education and Summer Session. Contains rectricted materials. English.
UA.25.43.0001
Language: English.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
Transfer; 1992; A92-91 (Boxes 1-16)
Transfer; 1991; A91-112 (Box 24)
Unknown source; 1989; A89-0029 (Box 23)
Transfer; 1989; A89-28 (Boxes 17 and 23)
Transfer; 1982; A82-57 (Boxes 18-22)
Transfer; 1984 A84-50 (Box 24)
Transfer; 1982; A82-79 (Box 25)
Transfer; 1976; 76-121 (Boxes 26)
Historical Note
The Duke University Center for Continuing Education (formerly known as the Office of Career Development and Continuing Education) was established in September 1969, with funds from the Alumni Association of the Woman's College. The Center was oriented toward satisfying the educational needs of women beyond college age and helping women find educational and professional programs in the Triangle area that best fit their career goals and family situations. The Center especially focused on undergraduate women, but later developed into a way for older women to reenter the Duke community by completing interrupted education, re-training or updating skills, changing careers, or developing new interests. Jean O'Barr was director of Continuing Education from 1971 to 1983.
The Office of Career Development and Continuing Education, active from about 1969 to 1975, provided undergraduate and continuing education students with assistance in establishing career goals. Working in cooperation with the University Counseling Center, the Office of Placement Services, and deans in the undergraduate colleges and professional schools, the Office sponsored the Apprenticeship Program, which arranged volunteer placement in community businesses and agencies and the Continuing Education Program which used student teachers, tutors, and assistants in meeting community needs. Other internship projects included helping local Girl Scouts groups, tutoring school-aged children, working in hospitals, counseling older adults, and acting as mentors to at-risk youth. The Office also worked with other campus organizations to bring professionals to speak on campus about the issues of young women in a professional work environment. Although the Office of Career Development and Continuing Education worked with both men and women, the Office was especially collaborative with student groups interested in women's programs and studies.
Around 1975, the Office of Career Development and Continuing Education became part of the Office of Continuing Education. The Office continued to perform many of the same services for students, but with less focus on young women professionals. The development of the Women's Studies Program at Duke University (1983) and other activities on campus continued to support young women's professional development.
The Office of Continuing Education functioned in cooperation with the Counseling Center and Appointments Office (later the Office of Placement Services and the Career Center). The Office of Continuing Education worked closely with student groups and programs of the Woman's College, such as Directions for Education of Women (DEW), a committee organized to inform women of career opportunities and to encourage them to coordinate career and family plans, and the Internship Program in Community Service, organized to place student volunteers of the Woman's College in community services. Service expanded to include year-round training, short courses, certificate programs, and credit courses for male and female students and non-students wishing to further their educations or prepare for standardized tests.
Jean O'Barr was the Director of the Office of Continuing Education from 1971 to 1983. During that time, she developed conferences about women and work, and guided the Institute for Learning in Retirement and the Peer Counseling Program. In 1983, she left the Office of Continuing Education to become Director of the Women's Studies Program at Duke University. In 1992, the Office of Continuing Education merged with the Summer Session Department to form the Office of Continuing Education and Summer Session. In 2003, the name changed again to the Office of Continuing Studies.
Collection Overview
Contains undergraduate and graduate student records, curriculum planning, and administrative materials related to the Office of Continuing Education (formerly known as Office of Career Development and Continuing Education) at Duke University. Office of Continuing Education was directed by Jean O'Barr from 1971 to 1983, and functioned in cooperation with the Appointments Office (later the Office of Placement Services and the Career Center) and the Woman's College. The Office initially focused on career development of women students, but expanded to offer guidance services to all students. In 1992, the Office of Continuing Education merged with the Summer Session Department to form the Office of Continuing Education and Summer Session. The records include student records, correspondence, progress reports, program proposals, newsletters, annual reports, minutes, flyers, pamphlets, clippings, grant applications, directories, and course schedules. Undergraduate and graduate student records are ordered alphabetically by last name of student. Subject files are ordered alphabetically. Contains restricted materials.
Subject Headings
Continuing education centers -- North Carolina -- Durham; Adult education; Career education -- North Carolina; Career education -- North Carolina -- Planning -- Handbooks, manuals, etc.; Duke University. Appointments Office; Duke University. Office of Continuing Education; Duke University. Office of Placement Services; Duke University. Woman's College -- History; Duke University -- Students; O'Barr, Jean F.; Occupational training for women; Vocational guidance; Vocational guidance for women -- North Carolina; Vocational guidance for women; Women -- Employment
Preliminary Description of the Collection
- Container List:
  The contents of Boxes 1-16, Undergraduate and Graduate student records, are RESTRICTED.
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Aml-Bro (Box 1)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Bog-Coleman, Je (Box 2)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Coleman, Ju-Drap (Box 3)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Drau-Ghir (Box 4)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Gian-Haye (Box 5)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Hea-Jon (Box 6)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Jord-Levy (Box 7)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Lew-Men (Box 8)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Mer-O'Ga (Box 9)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Ogi-Reynal (Box 10)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Reynolds-Shaw, F (Box 11)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Shaw, R-Stud (Box 12)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Stuh-Watkins, P (Box 13)
  - Undergraduate student records, 1970-1992, Watkins, S-Zw (Box 14)
  - Graduate student records, 1970-1992, A-O (Box 15)
  - Graduate student records, 1970-1992, P-Z (Box 16)
  - Access Project (Box 17)
  - Alternative Work Patterns Proposal (Box 17)
  - Alumni (Box 17)
  - Astin study (Box 17)
  - Ball's proposal for continuing education (Box 17)
  - Blind services (Box 17)
  - Browning Conference (Box 17)
  - Cable TV (Box 17)
  - Report, career development course (Box 17)
  - Career workshops, [2 folders] (Box 17)
  - Careers for Humanists (Box 17)
  - Cell Leaders in Tanzania (Box 17)
  - City Hall dedication (Box 17)
  - Conferences (Box 17)
  - Cocktail party with women faculty (Box 17)
  - Conference, Law Day (Box 17)
  - Conference, Second Careers for Women (Box 17)
  - Conference, "Need Assessment" conference and training (Box 17)
  - Conference, Take Charge! (Box 17)
  - Conference, Where the Jobs Are (Box 17)
  - Conference materials (Box 17)
  - Covitz, Sharon (Box 17)
  - Education Committee, Stagville (Box 17)
  - EPA vocational counseling (Box 17)
  - Faculty advising (Box 17)
  - Flowers (Box 17)
  - Foreign diplomat fellows program (Box 17)
  - George Washington University, June 9-10 conference (Box 17)
  - Governor's conference (Box 17)
  - Governor's conference on mental health (Box 17)
  - IDC (Box 17)
  - Jansen, Roxy (Box 17)
  - Junior League (Box 17)
  - Loblolly (Box 17)
  - The Major Step (Box 17)
  - Math Proposal (Box 17)
  - Medtronic, Inc. (Box 18)
  - N.C. Humanities Values Conference (Box 18)
  - Nees, Monica (Box 18)
  - NUEA/NEA workshop application (Box 18)
  - Nose Against the Window Pane (Box 18)
  - Panel, Conversation in Continuing Education (Box 18)
  - Panel, Career Choices Women Make, and Careers in Communication (Box 18)
  - Panel, Careers in Education (Box 18)
  - Panel, Careers in Counseling (Box 18)
  - Panel, Health Career (Box 18)
  - Peer Counseling Development Program (Box 18)
  - Pre-Retirement seminar (Box 18)
  - Program for Retired Professionals (Box 18)
  - Project Upstart (Box 18)
  - Quinney, Valeria (Box 18)
  - Seminar in Writing (Box 18)
  - Self-evaluation report (Box 18)
  - Seminar, Careers for Humanities (Box 18)
  - Smeal reception (Box 18)
  - Sociology Department (Box 18)
  - State meeting for women in NCCE (Box 18)
  - State summer course (Box 18)
  - Survey, HE61S (Box 18)
  - Tanglewood (Box 18)
  - Title IV self-evaluation (Box 18)
  - Tutorial article on adult leadership (Box 18)
  - Wellesley conference (Box 18)
  - Women in medicine (Box 18)
  - Workshop on Older Women Alone (Box 18)
  - Workshop, September 24, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Year-round operation (Box 18)
  - East Campus Committee files, 1978-1979
    - General lists of courses and people on committees (Box 18)
    - Long Range planning, East Campus library planning materials (Box 18)
    - Board of Housing, Residential Life Committee (Box 18)
    - Women on East Campus, statistics of residents (Box 18)
    - Agendas and Minutes and correspondence (Box 18)
    - Residential Life Committee (Box 18)
  - Clippings, general publicity, 1969-1980 (Box 19)
  - Short talks notes (generally women in the work force), ca. 1973-1976 (Box 19)
  - Speaking engagements of Continuing Education staff (Box 19)
  - Conference announcements and supplementary materials (Box 19)
  - General correspondence between office staff, ca. 1974-1979 (Box 20)
  - Fliers and announcements for seminars, panels, conference sponsored by the Office of Continuing Education (Box 20)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Continuing Education, minutes, 1970-1972 (Box 20)
  - Center for Continuing Education, handbooks, 1972-1974 (Box 20)
  - Second Careers Conference materials, 1974 (Box 20)
  - Position descriptions and office correspondence (Box 20)
  - Seminar materials (fliers, notes, registration lists, course evaluations) (Box 20)
  - Continuing Education of Women, correspondence, programs, notes, ca. 1971-1972 (Box 21)
  - Class visitation (Box 21)
  - Tuition and special cases for tuition remission (Box 21)
  - Undergraduate Faculty Council speech, 1969 (Box 21)
  - General counseling and admission Materials range in date from (Box 21)
  - Course materials, fliers, brochures, lists, notes, correspondence, course evaluations, 1977-Spring 1978 (Box 21)
  - Course materials, fliers, brochures, lists, notes, correspondence, course evaluations, Summer 1978-1980 (Box 21)
  - Course materials, fliers, brochures, lists, notes, correspondence, course evaluations, Summer 1978-1980 (Box 22)
  - Carolina Consulting Scientists and Engineers, Inc., 1979-1985 Includes minutes, grant requests, publicity, incorporation papers, conference materials, correspondence, flyers, financial materials, directories. (Box 23)
  - Lecture Series notices, 1974-1983 (Box 24)
  - Dual Careers Conference, 1978 (Box 24)
  - The Scholar's Letter, 1983-1985 (Box 24)
  - Pamphlets (Box 24)
  - Fliers, brochures, clippings (Box 24)
  - Clippings (Box 24)
  - Miscellaneous printer materials (Box 24)
  - Annual reports, 1981-1988 (Box 25)
  - Course offerings, 1972-1984 (Box 25)
  - Handbooks, 1974-1976, 1987 (Box 25)
  - Course catalogs, 1985-1992 (Box 26)
  - Tutoring, projects, correspondence, 1969-1973 (Box 27)
  - Course evaluations, 1969-1973 (Box 27)
  - Correspondence, 1971-1973 (Box 27)
  - Internships in social services, 1969-1973 (Box 27)
  - Course materials, fliers, brochures, lists, notes, correspondence, course evaluations, 1968-1972 (Box 27)
  - Insternship announcements in Spectrum newsletter, ca 1972 (Box 27)
  - Handbooks, continuing education, general internship, ca. 1974-1979 (Box 28)
  - Internship announcements, notes and correpsondence, 1967-1971 (Box 28)
  - Internship evaluations, 1967-1971 (Box 28)
  - Directions for Educated Women Committee conference materials, correspondence, fliers, brochures, annual reports, 1965-1971 (Box 28)
  - Directions for Educated Women Committee, annual reports, 1965-1971 (Box 28)
  - Engineering program correspondence, ca. 1975 (Box 28)
  - General engineering jobs recruiting (Box 28)
  - YWCA (Box 28)
  - Women in Action (Box 28)
  - Episcopal Student Center (Box 28)
  - National Organization for Women, task force and conference materials, ca. 1975 (Box 28)
  - Women in higher education reports (Box 28)
  - Early women's studies pamphlets (Box 28)
  - U.S. Department of Labor, discussion on women in the work force and general education of women (Box 28)
  - Conference materials (Box 28)
  - Clippings (Box 28)
  - Directions for Educated Women (DEW) materials (Box 28)
  - Status of women in Research Triangle Park businesses (Box 28)
  - Bibliographies on women (for courses and general reference) (Box 28)
Related Material
Appointments Office records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Center for Continuing Education and Summer Session records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Office of Placement Services records.
University Archives, Duke University.